It's been too long, Uncle Viktor.
（トーリ）叔父様
ご無沙汰しております
It certainly has, Torri.
（ザハリアス）
久しぶりだな トーリ
This is my wife, Vera.
彼女が妻のヴェーラだ
It's a pleasure, madam.
（トーリ）
ご機嫌麗しゅう 奥様
Thank you for inviting us.
（ヴェーラ）
お招きいただき感謝します
It seems that bombing wiped out
most of the pro-special-zone advocates.
例の爆破事件で 推進派が
ほとんどいなくなったようだな
It's a relief, in a sense.
ある意味 すっきりしました
This headquarters has grown.
この本部も以前より広くなった
Yes, as we've gained adherents,
はい 信者も増え より効率的に
教えを伝えるシステムも―
we've expanded our system
to deliver our teachings more effectively.
拡張を重ねています
Here, Uncle Viktor.
叔父様 こちらを
Your usual security passes.
いつものセキュリティーパスです
Thank you.
（ザハリアス）ありがとう
OK, this place looks safe.
（ザハリアス）オーケー
ここは安全のようだ
We got in successfully.
うまく潜り込めたな
They didn't suspect us at all.
（如月(きさらぎ)）全く疑われていませんね
Unauthorized full-body holos are illegal.
（炯(けい)）全身ホロは無許可だと違法だ
I doubt they would be expecting them.
連中にとっても想定外なんだろう
Um...
（如月）あの…
What is it?
（炯）どうした？
I'm sorry about what happened earlier.
この前は申し訳ありませんでした
You shielded me from the blast.
I won't disgrace myself like that again.
爆発から守っていただいて
もう あんな醜態は さらしません
Don't worry.
気にするな
Please do the same for me.
俺が危ない時は頼む
あっ… はい！
Yes, sir.
First, we search for bombs and
Sister Shinogi, thought to be in hiding.
（炯）まずは 潜伏中と思われる
シスター陵駕(しのぎ)と爆弾の捜索だ
And the reclusive founder, Nisei.
（如月）そして
姿を見せない教祖の仁世(にせい)
Yes.
（炯）ああ
That's the rundown
on the serial terrorist bombings.
（雛河(ひなかわ)）以上が
連続爆破テロの概略です
The undercover investigation's just begun,
so I can't comment on it.
潜入捜査については
始まったばかりで何とも言えません
Apart from that, we're reinvestigating
the previous inspectors' accident.
それとは別に 前任の
監視官の事故を再調査しています
That's all.
では
ふう…
Disgusting.
（霜月(しもつき)）気色悪い
（雛河）うわあっ！
I don't approve of what you're doing.
どうかと思うわよ そういうの
Yes, ma'am.
（雛河）は… はい
Prioritize the present Unit One,
not the past one.
昔の一係じゃなく
今の一係を優先しなさい
Yes, ma'am. Of course.
はい もちろん
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
♪～
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the lost memories that flee
once they're liberated and banished
Are an everlasting cubism.
Cause I know that in a future gone mad,
Even nightmares are peaceful.
RESET, RESET, yeah.
The midnight sun
awakens and turns to a riot.
A gun for a faux-friendly kiss.
A knife for a faux-revolutionary hug.
Get rid of it all, even the frozen chains.
Reality is always outside your head.
In a world seen through bestial eyes,
There is neither darkness nor light.
Draw the knives
locked behind your eyelids.
Reap the lives that grow into shackles.
Even the false memories that flash before
your eyes impatiently and impulsively
Are an everlasting cubism.
～♪
#06
Caesar's Gold Coins
I decoded the data we found.
（志恩(しおん)）見つかった
データを解読した
Sister Shinogi and Kurisu O'Brien
jointly rent a warehouse.
シスター陵駕は
久利須(くりす)･オブライエンと―
貸し倉庫を共同保有してるわ
They deliver a lot of goods
to New Town from there.
そこから大量の何かを
ニュータウンに運んでるみたい
We've arrived. Starting the investigation.
（灼(あらた)）現場到着 今から調べます
According to my data, Sister Shinogi
and O'Brien from Immigration
（六合塚(くにづか)）情報だと―
シスター陵駕と
入管のオブライエンが―
definitely worked to expedite
the naturalization process for refugees.
難民相手に国籍付与の便宜を
図ってたのは間違いない
The condition was abandoning
their property. So, a bribe?
（灼）条件は財産の放棄
つまり 賄賂？
Yes. And because they disarmed
refugees in Dejima,
（六合塚）ええ
出島で難民の武装解除を
行っていたから―
they could have obtained
military explosives.
軍用爆薬を入手することも
可能だった
OK.
（入江(いりえ)）オーケー
ここは危険物なしだ
Nothing hazardous here.
Five beds showing signs of use.
（灼）使用した形跡のベッドが５つ
Meaning there are
three more human bombs?
（入江）ってことは
爆弾人間が あと３人？
I'm picking up trace amounts
of vaporized elements.
（天馬(てんま)）気化した微量の成分を感知
They match the explosive used
in the attack.
テロに使用された爆薬と合致したぞ
Shion, do you have management data
for this place?
（灼）志恩さん
ここの管理データ 残ってます？
It's all intact.
（志恩）ばっちりよ
The destination is the factory
in New Town.
行き先は
ニュータウンの工場になってるわ
That's Auma's turf.
He has to know about it.
（入江）あそこを仕切ってんのは
アウマだ 知らないわけがねえ
They're linked.
（天馬）つながったな
シスター陵駕とアウマ
Sister Shinogi and Auma.
ん…
At present, we have
roughly 40 thousand adherents.
（トーリ）
現在 信者の数は４万人ほど―
Of those, around 500 lead
a communal life in our headquarters.
そのうち約500人が教団本部で
共同生活を送っています
As immigrants with clouded Hues,
色相が濁った彼らは―
they would otherwise be passed
from facility to facility.
入国者であることを理由に
施設をたらい回しに
It was Founder Nisei who reached out
a hand of salvation to them.
そんな彼らに
救いの手を差し伸べたのが―
仁世教祖です
Their Hues improved quickly
upon their conversion.
入信した彼らの色相は
すぐに改善しました
Magnificent.
すばらしい
久々に ミスター仁世と話したいな
I'd like to speak to Mr. Nisei.
It's been so long.
んん…
Very well. I will take you to him.
分かりました ご案内します
My humble apologies,
（トーリ）申し訳ないのですが―
but he is engaged in special prayer.
No one may speak to him.
特別祈とう中のため
誰も話しかけてはなりません
He prays all the time?
（ザハリアス）
ずっと祈り続けているのか？
Yes. When true inner peace comes to him,
（トーリ）ええ
真に心の平和が訪れる時―
he will deign to speak with us once more.
再び私たちと話してくださいます
Let go of me!
（信者）放してください
Be silent, bottom.
（ドクター）黙れ ボトム
How violent.
（ザハリアス）物騒だね
A bottom, one of our least faithful
adherents, must have caused trouble.
信心が足らない最底辺の信者―
ボトムが暴れたのでしょう
Who were the masked people?
マスクをかぶった者たちは？
They're called "doctors,"
a rank we recently established.
（トーリ）最近 作られた階級で
ドクターと呼ばれる―
They are the elite here.
ここのエリートたちです
I'm terribly sorry you had to see that.
（二瓶(にへい)）お見苦しいところを
申し訳ない
This is the leader of the doctors,
Dr. Saburo Nihei.
ドクターのリーダー
二瓶三郎(さぶろう)博士です
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
以後 お見知りおきを
We'll have to sneak by them
to talk to the founder.
（炯）教祖と話すには
連中の目を盗むしかないな
Yes, sir.
（如月）はい
During the day, we'll join in the therapy
and gather information from members.
それと
日中はセラピーに参加し―
信者たちから情報を集める
We'll participate in the therapy?
（如月）
セラピーに参加するんですか？
Is that a problem?
何か問題が？
あ…
It's just not possible to improve
your Hue that quickly.
色相が すぐ改善されるなんて
絶対ありえないのに
Why do they believe that fraud?
何で あんなペテンを
信じるんでしょう？
Does religion just prey on the weak?
弱者に つけ込むのが宗教ですか？
Maybe they need someone to reach out
to them when everyone has abandoned them.
誰からも見放された時―
手を差し伸べてくれる存在は
必要じゃないか？
I'm surprised you'd say that.
意外な言葉ですね
What kind of person do you think I am?
（炯）
俺をどんな人間だと思ってるんだ
A person who doesn't need help.
助けを必要としない人かと
フッ
Everyone needs help.
そんな人間は いないよ
（パトカーのサイレン）
What the...?
何だ？
Short-term treatment of your wife's Hue
may prove difficult.
（二瓶）奥様の色相ですが
短期間での治療は難しいでしょう
I advise long-term therapy.
長期セラピーを提案します
I'd like her to be able to live
in this country soon. Can you help us?
早く 彼女をこの国に住まわせたい
どうにかならないか？
Actually, there is a method
called Eternal White.
実は
エターナルホワイトという―
It's a treatment that can keep
any Hue clear for good.
どんな色相でも
永続的にクリアになる―
特別な治療法が…
Torri, sir.
（側近）トーリ代行
There's been another bombing.
Joseph Auma is dead.
新たな自爆テロです
アウマ上人が死亡
The factory district sustained damage.
工場地帯に被害が出ました
Uncle Viktor,
（トーリ）叔父様
we've secured sufficient packages for you.
お渡しする荷物は
十分 確保してありますが―
Would you like to check them,
if you're uncertain?
もし心配でしたら
確認されますか？
Yes, I'd like that.
（ザハリアス）そうだな 頼む
Venerable Auma!
Why did this have to happen?
（僧侶たち）上人様
何で このような…
So, a bomb got him in the end.
（入江）最期は爆弾でおだぶつか
（通信機の着信音）
（入江）あっ
The suicide bomber was Samuel Minnie,
（志恩）
自爆犯はサミュエル･ミニー
a former member of Heaven's Leap.
やはり ヘブンズリープの元信者よ
Wasn't Auma in league with the perps?
アウマは
犯人の仲間じゃねえのかよ？
And unlike the other victims,
he's anti-special-zone.
それに 今までの被害者と違って
特区反対派だぞ
（入江･天馬）ん？
（息を吸う音）
んっ
Forget it, Inspector.
やめとけ 監視官
Forget what?
何ですか？
You'll collapse like you did before.
また この前みたく倒れっぞ
フッ
I'm curious about that.
あれが気になって
Why did Joseph Auma
flee all the way here in a truck?
何で アウマ上人は
トラックを運転し―
こんな場所に
逃げてきたんだろうって
Did he know a bomber was coming?
（天馬）自爆犯が来るって
分かってたのか？
Yes, probably.
（灼）ええ たぶん
And he didn't run. He knocked the bomber
into the reservoir and died with him.
しかも 自爆犯から逃げずに―
犯人を貯水池に落とし
爆発に巻き込まれた
Was it to protect the factory?
（六合塚）工場を守るためでは？
This facility supplies water
to the factory.
（灼）工場用水を供給する施設です
The factory couldn't run
if it were destroyed.
破壊されれば
むしろ 工場が稼働できない
But on that side,
there's only a dilapidated old building.
逆に あちらは
老朽化した廃屋があるだけ
I see.
（六合塚）なるほど
Letting it go off in the storehouse
would have caused less damage.
資材置き場で自爆させたほうが
被害はなかった
Meaning...
つまり…
Joseph Auma died defending it.
アウマ上人は あれを守って
死んだということです
（天馬と入江の力み声）
（２人）なっ
（女性たちのざわめき）
Look what they've been hiding.
（入江）
なんてものを隠してやがった
What the hell are you running here?!
お前ら 何やってんだ こら！
Nothing.
（僧侶）違います
Their pimp was a pro-special-zone
advocate, who died in the attack.
先日の爆破で―
特区推進派だった
売春の元締めが死にました
We took the opportunity to help them
escape their brothels.
その混乱に乗じて
売春窟から彼らを逃がしたのです
I've heard that an organization
is forcing immigrants
色相悪化で
強制送還されるはずの入国者に―
at risk of deportation
for deteriorating Hues into prostitution.
売春を強要する組織があると
聞いてはいたわ
Why don't they report it to Public Safety?
何で公安局に通報しねえんだ
When they could all be latent criminals?
全員 潜在犯候補なのに？
あっ
Joseph Auma
opposed the prostitution ring.
アウマ上人は売春組織と敵対してた
He gave up his life to protect them
because they couldn't escape.
そして 逃げられない彼らを守って
命を落とした
That's right.
（僧侶）そのとおりです
They're all gonna be institutionalized.
What'll you do?
全員 このままじゃ 施設行きだ
どうするつもりなんだ？
We'll protect them.
（僧侶）我らが保護します
What can you do without Joseph Auma?!
アウマ上人を失ったあなたたちに
何ができるんですか！
Well...
（僧侶）うっ
（僧侶）それは…
I'll work something out.
俺が掛け合ってみます
I'd like to use Dejima.
（霜月）出島を使いたいんだけど
Where did this come from?
（花城(はなしろ)）やぶから棒に
何なのよ あなた
My subordinates found a large number
of immigrants forced into prostitution.
（霜月）うちの部下が―
強制売春の被害者を
大量に見つけちゃって
I see. You want to move them
to Dejima for psychological care?
（花城）ふーん
出島に移して メンタルケアを？
I really don't care what happens
to immigrants with clouded Hues.
（霜月）私は
色相が濁った入国者なんて―
どうでもいいんだけど
I'm saying I'll owe you one. Understand?
いい？　借りにしておくって
言ってるの
（花城）ふう…
People don't bow and scrape
to people they can't stand
人間はね
どうでもいいことのために―
for things they don't care about.
気に入らない相手に
頭 下げたりしないわ
うっ…
I'll see to it.
手続きするわ
By the way, you're not looking
into Heaven's Leap, are you?
ところで―
ヘブンズリープに関して
妙なこと始めてない？
What do you mean?
何の話？
Stay out of our business.
（花城）余計なことは しないで
It's our jurisdiction. If anyone's
not minding their own business, it's you.
（霜月）公安局の管轄よ
余計なことをするとしたら
そっちでしょ？
You can play dumb if you like,
（花城）とぼけるなら
それでいいけど
but try not to get too deep in my debt.
あんまり 私に
貸しを作りすぎないようにね
This is Shimotsuki.
（霜月）こちら霜月
How'd it go?
どうでした？
I've worked something out.
何とかなりそうだけど…
But your job is to protect people
with healthy Hues. Understand?
いい？　あなたの仕事は
色相が健康な人間を守ることなの
Yes, ma'am.
はい
You can show pity on the weak, but don't
forget the Public Safety Bureau's mission.
弱者への同情もいいけど―
公安局の本分を忘れないように
Keep that in mind.
以後 気をつけてね
We'll give them care at Dejima.
彼らを出島でケアします
Venerable Auma would be delighted.
アウマ上人も お喜びになります
Auma must have been protecting
more than them.
上人が守ろうとしたのは
彼らだけじゃないはず
Show us what's through here.
この先にあるものを
見せてください
（２人）ん…
Now we have proof.
これで裏付けが取れましたね
The anti-special-zone faction
is linked to a smuggling group?
特区反対派は
やはり 密輸グループと関わりが？
Yes.
（炯）ああ
There's no doubt.
間違いないだろう
That alone would be enough evidence
for a compulsory search.
あれだけでも
強制捜査の証拠には十分ですが
This organization won't
go down so easily.
そんな簡単な組織じゃないぞ
ここは
We need the founder's confession
and a bomb.
教祖の自供と爆弾の現物が欲しい
This is the last place we haven't looked.
未確認の場所は ここで最後です
（車輪の進む音）
（２人）ん？
Grant this soul
the grace of Eternal White.
この者に
エターナルホワイトの加護を
May Sibyl's blessings be upon you.
シビュラの祝福あれ
They look like life-support devices
for people in vegetative states.
植物状態の人間を生かす
延命装置のようです
Are all of these...?
これ すべて…
ん… はっ
They're participants in that "program."
Their charts are in here.
例のプログラム適用者
ここの患者カルテだ
Look at this.
（如月）見てください
Marcel Cotard. The suicide bomber.
マルセル･コタール 自爆犯
The notes are strange.
変な備考が
（スキャンの音）
"Attention required."
"CO-related subject."
“要注意” “Ｃ･Ｏ関連対象”
“白紙化リスト入り”
"Add to expunge list."
The second bomber has a chart, too.
第２の自爆犯のカルテもあります
CO-Related
"Related subject" and "expunge"...
（炯）
“関連対象”に“白紙化”―
There are five charts marked "CO-Related."
“Ｃ･Ｏ関連”と
ついたカルテは５人分―
As many as there are bombs.
爆弾の数と一致する
All the bombers qualified for the program.
自爆犯は全員 プログラム適用者だ
All five were moved to New Town first.
５人とも ニュータウンに
移されたあとです
Probably with Sister Shinogi.
恐らく シスター陵駕と一緒に
（炯）はっ
（如月）はっ 教祖代行のサイン
The representative's signature?
Torri Aschenbach.
（炯）トーリ･アッシェンバッハ
Is he the mastermind?
すべて やつの主導なのか
Little Torri's doing well.
Don't you agree, madam?
（梓澤(あずさわ)）トーリ君
うまくやってますね 奥様
Who are you calling "madam"?
（裁園寺(さいおんじ)）何が奥様よ
You don't need to butter me up.
私の機嫌を取る必要などないわ
I beg your pardon.
それは失礼しました
Still, this Special Religious Zone
is a tough task.
ただ 今回の信仰特区は難しい
I mean it.
お世辞じゃないですよ
Thank you for the warning.
ご忠告ありがとう
Do you want to be a congressman?
あなた
コングレスマンになりたいの？
Yes, all inspectors
aim for that lofty position.
（梓澤）はい
インスペクターは 皆―
その高みを目指しております
To get closer to the truth of the world.
世界の真実に近づくために
Truth, you say?
真実 ねえ…
Have I ever told you?
フッ 前にも言ったかしら
The only equal to Sibyl
in our society is Bifrost.
この社会で シビュラと対等なのは
ビフロストだけよ
I know that, of course.
もちろん 分かっております
Do your best to be chosen by Roundrobin.
（裁園寺）ラウンドロビンに
選ばれるように―
せいぜい 頑張りなさい
I call for an Inspection motion.
（裁園寺）インスペクト動議を要請
As a Relation Hedge,
リレーション･ヘッジとして―
I propose bailouts for the iron,
steel, and energy industries.
鉄鋼･エネルギー産業に対する
救済措置の実行を提案するわ
I oppose the motion.
（静火(しずか)）動議に反対します
I second the motion.
（代銀(しろがね)）私は動議に賛成だ
Invest in rail transportation.
（代銀）鉄道輸送業にインベスト
Disperse the production base.
生産拠点を分散
Generate reemployment for laborers.
労働者たちの再雇用を創出
Oh, my. Have you turned pro-special-zone?
あら 特区賛成派に転じるの？
I oppose the special zone.
（代銀）特区は反対だ
But for the sake
of restoring predatory economics,
だが 略奪経済復活のため
ニュータウンを―
I agree to making New Town
an international black market relay.
国際ブラックマーケットの
中継点にすることには賛成だよ
Then the motion is passed.
（裁園寺）では 動議を実行
Isn't it extravagant for the dealer
to propose a Relation Hedge?
（代銀）親がリレーション･
ヘッジを提案とは―
大盤振る舞いじゃないか
Have you guessed the relation?
（裁園寺）リレーションに
見当は ついた？
I wonder.
（代銀）さて どうだろう
The way you're going about this, Shizuka,
静火君のやり方だと―
you stand to incur incalculable losses
if Public Safety's investigation fails.
公安局が
捜査に失敗した時の損失は―
計り知れないぞ
That will be the end for me, then.
（静火）ならば
そこまでということです
So, these attacks are basically
to crush the pro-special-zone advocates?
（天馬）
で この事件は要するに―
特区推進派潰しなのか？
It looks like
there's more to it than that.
（灼）ただ 推進派を
潰してるわけじゃなさそうです
If we assume they had other reasons
to kill the bombing victims...
爆殺されたほうには―
されるだけの理由が
別にあったと考えれば
This seems likely to be involved.
関わりがありそうなものが これ
It was among Joseph Auma's effects.
アウマ上人の所持品なんだけど
I've identified it as a memento
of a refugee protection group in Dejima.
出島で難民保護をしていた
グループの記念品と分かったわ
（入江）ん？
確か シスターも持ってたな
I think the Sister had one, too.
Yes. They were given to four people.
（志恩）そう
配られた人物は４名
Kurisu, Nisei,
（雛河）久利須 仁世
陵駕 アウマ
Shinogi, and Auma.
There was a microchip
in the watch face.
時計盤の中には
マイクロチップを仕込んでたわ
What's on it?
（入江）チップの中身は？
It looks like some kind of plan.
（志恩）
何かの計画表みたいだけど―
It would require multiple chips
to reconstruct it.
複数のチップを組み合わせないと
復元できない
Multiple? You mean all four?
複数って つまり ４人分？
Without a doubt.
間違いなくね
What about the parts from the factory?
工場で見つけた部品の正体は？
They're "bolts,"
parts for foreign-made assault rifles.
（志恩）海外製の
アサルトライフルの―
ボルトって部品だったわ
I'm confused again.
また分かんなくなったぜ
Auma was helping prostitution victims
and smuggling guns at the same time?
アウマは強制売春の被害者を
助けながら―
銃を密売してたのか？
（入江）ああ？
It doesn't add up.
どうにも ちぐはぐだ
There must be a reason.
Let's look into it.
（灼）何か理由がある
そこを調べましょう
（入江）んっ
（天馬･雛河）は？
（２人）ん？
I know someone who knows their way
around these things.
この手の品に
詳しいやつの心当たりがある
You mind coming with me for a bit,
Inspector?
監視官 少し 面貸してくれるか？
あ…
フフッ
This is the place.
（入江）ここだ ここ
Antiques Shop
Follow me.
ついてきな
An antique shop?
（灼）アンティークショップ？
A gun-nut rich kid ended up
becoming a fence in the slums.
（入江）銃マニアのボンボンが―
スラムに流れて始めた故買屋さ
（ブローカー）ん？　うっわ！
い… 入江さんじゃないっすか
Well, if it isn't Irie!
I thought you were dead!
生きてたんすか？
Don't go killing me off,
or I'll kill you, moron.
勝手に殺すな バカ野郎 殺すぞ
But I heard Public Safety nabbed you.
（ブローカー）
でも 公安にパクられたって…
I'm a gumshoe for Public Safety now.
（入江）今の俺は公安局のデカだよ
He's my boss, an inspector.
こっちは上司の監視官
What?!
（ブローカー）えっ！
Listen, my boss is just itching
to kill someone.
いいか 俺の上司は
人を殺したくて うずうずしてる
（灼）おっ
なっ…
You got that right.
（灼）そのとおりだ
I killed four people just yesterday.
昨日も ４人は殺しちまったぜ
For real?
（灼）ヘヘヘッ
（ブローカー）マジか…
Does this ring any bells?
（入江）こいつに見覚えがあるか？
（ブローカー）おっ
That's a high-quality bolt for an AK-Alfa!
上物のAK･ALFA(アルファ)の
ボルトじゃないっすか
Where'd you get it?
どこで手に入れたんですか？
Don't play dumb.
How are you selling these?
（ブローカー）うっ ああっ
（入江）とぼけんじゃねえ
こいつをどうやって
売りさばいてんだ？
No idea. A semi-automatic rifle is more
than a slum-dweller can hope for.
し… 知りませんよ
スラム住人でも
自動小銃なんて手に余る
A factory was mass-producing these.
こいつは ある工場で
大量生産されてた
There must be plenty on the black market.
裏で相当な数が出回ってるだろうが
So that must be...
じゃあ これが…
おっ ううっ
You know something?
何か知ってんのか？
There are rumors about Japanese-
made standardized parts on the market.
た… 確かに 日本製の規格品が
出回り始めたって―
やばいウワサが
You mean domestically?
国内の話か？
They're distributed overseas.
流通は海外です
I hear high-quality Japanese parts
sell like crazy in conflict zones.
高品質な日本製のパーツが―
紛争地帯で
バカ売れしてるって話が…
But I also hear they might break
in weird ways.
でも 確か 変な壊れ方
するとか しないとか
Well, precision parts are valuable, so
they go for prices you wouldn't believe.
まあ 何だろうと
精密パーツは貴重なんで―
すげえ値段で
取り引きされるらしいっす
My holo is running low.
（ヴェーラ）ホロの充電が
少なくなってます
We have no time. Turn it off.
（ザハリアス）
時間はない ホロを消す
ん？
Founder Nisei.
仁世教祖？
（炯）なっ
（如月）あっ
A hologram.
（炯）ホログラム！
あっ
Inspector.
監視官
So, he's the real Nisei?
（炯）彼が本物の仁世か
He's alive, but in a vegetative state.
（如月）生きてはいますが
植物状態のようです
He couldn't direct crimes
in this condition.
（炯）これでは
犯行の指示など不可能だな
Who's there?
（トーリ）
そこにいるのは誰ですか？
Oh, Torri.
（ザハリアス）トーリか
Uncle Viktor. What are you doing here?
（トーリ）叔父様
何をしているのです
I just wanted to speak to the founder.
（ザハリアス）
つい 教祖に話しかけてね
I'm shocked. Why didn't you tell me?
驚いたよ
どうして言ってくれなかったんだ？
Mulberry purple.
マルベリー･パープル
A Hue this clouded means quarantine.
これだけ濁れば 隔離は免れない
It's my Hue when I converted, madam.
私の入信時の色相です 奥様
You recovered from this state?
（ヴェーラ）この状態から回復を？
It is all thanks to the founder's works.
すべては教祖様の御業のおかげです
In order to repay my debt to him,
私は教祖様に恩返しするため―
I developed a way
to make Hues even clearer.
さらに色相をクリアにする方法を
開発しました
Developed?
開発？
Treatment using
the ultimate state of mind, Eternal White.
至高の境地―
エターナルホワイトによる
治療法です
Shockingly white, isn't it?
This is how far humans can go.
驚くほどの白さでしょう
人間は ここまでいけるんだ
New Town has at last become
a power vacuum.
ニュータウンは ようやく
権力の空白地帯となった
In accordance with Sibyl's blessings,
シビュラの祝福に従い―
I will build a paradise
to welcome the founder there.
教祖様をお迎えする楽園が
かの地に築かれる
（ザハリアス･ヴェーラ）はっ
I never expected the Public Safety Bureau
to launch an undercover investigation.
まさか 公安局が
潜入捜査を仕掛けてくるなんてね
How did you know?
（ザハリアス）なぜ 分かった？
When you heard of Auma's death,
アウマの死を聞いた時ですよ
it startled your wife.
あなたの奥様が動揺された
That reaction was out of character.
（トーリ）ありえない反応です
（如月）ううっ
I wanted to leave you free
to flush out MOFA spies,
泳がせて 外務省のスパイを
押さえたかったのですが―
but things are different
now that you've seen the founder.
教祖様の姿を見られては
放置できません
Foreign Affairs?
外務省だと？
You're a poor actor.
下手な演技だ
Hello, First.
（トーリ）どうも ファースト
Hard at work, I see, Third.
（梓澤）サード 頑張ってるねえ
I'm flattered.
（トーリ）それはもう
（炯）はっ
（梓澤）ふむ
Young lady, red roses would suit you
お嬢さん あなたには手錠より―
better than handcuffs. What a shame.
真っ赤な花が似合うのに 残念
（如月）うっ
Are you OK with the founder's absence?
（梓澤）教祖不在で大丈夫かい？
The founder is present.
不在では ありませんよ
That's a disease
called eustress deficiency, Third.
（梓澤）サード
あれは ユーストレス欠乏症
っていう病気だよ
It is no disease.
（トーリ）病気ではない
フッ
You're incredible, in a way.
ある意味 君はすごいよ
You invented a system that can induce
eustress deficiency in others.
他人をユーストレス欠乏症に
誘導できるシステムを―
作ったんだから
It is the state of Eternal White.
エターナルホワイトの境地です
Would you care to undergo treatment,
First? You'll be happy.
ファーストも治療されたら
どうですか？
幸せになれますよ
I love my job
more than personal happiness.
俺は 個人の幸福より
仕事を愛してるからねえ
But I'm worried about your Hues.
でも 心配だなあ 君らの色相
Excessive violence leads
to Psycho-Pass deterioration.
度を超した暴力は
サイコパスの悪化を呼ぶ
Of course. Violence not permitted
by Sibyl is abominable.
もちろん シビュラが許さぬ暴力は
忌むべきもの
So?
（梓澤）で？
I'll use the survivors of Peacebreaker.
ピースブレイカーの生き残りを使う
The two pathfinders?
You'd use those lowlifes?
パスファインダーの２人？
あんな下品なの使うの？
National Center for Medical Research
The operation was a total success.
（灼）手術 大成功だって
You'll be able to see Kei's face
in a few days.
あと数日すれば
炯の顔が見られるよ
Is Kei working?
（舞子(まいこ)）炯は仕事中？
Sorry.
（灼）ごめんね
（舞子）フッ 何で謝るの？
Why apologize?
I'm sorry that I'll be the first
person you get to see.
いや 目が見えるようになって
最初に視界に入るのが俺じゃ―
申し訳ないよ
Don't be. Thank you.
そんなことない
ありがとう 声を聞けて うれしい
I'm happy to hear your voice.
I'm glad you're relieved.
安心したんなら よかった フッ
Um...
（舞子）あの…
（灼）ん？
I want to ask you a favor about Kei.
炯のことでお願いがあるんだけど
What?
（灼）何？
He always believes that
he can protect people.
あの人
いつも誰かを守れると思ってる
But people like him
are always the ones being protected.
でも そういう人ほど
誰かに守られてるものよ
Kei doesn't realize that.
炯には その自覚がないから
I know, but I can't help relying on him.
（灼）分かってる でも
つい 炯を頼りにしちゃうんだよな
If you can protect each other,
I'm sure you'll be fine.
２人で守り合えるなら―
きっと大丈夫
I know.
（灼）分かってる
（舞子）フッ
Sorry for taking a detour.
寄り道しちゃって
すいませんでした
Don't be. It was on the way.
どうせ通り道だ 気にすんな
I still don't get it.
しっかし 分からねえなあ
Where in New Town
did the Sister hide the goods?
シスターは ニュータウンのどこに
ブツを隠してるってんだ？
Someplace hard to find, I'd guess.
（入江）そりゃ
見つかりにくいとこだろ
あっ
The rental cars...
リースカー…
I'm sorry I asked such a big favor.
（灼）すいませんね 無理言って
Anything for Public Safety.
（シスター）
公安局の捜査ということなら
（物音）
（天馬）ん？
（中身が動く音）
These are the parts they made
in the factory!
こりゃ 工場で
作ってやがった部品だぞ
Let's check the other cars.
他の車両も確認しましょう
What are these white rocks?
何だ？　この白い石は
Rough diamonds.
（灼）ダイヤモンドの原石です
Seriously?!
マジか！
Diamonds are synonymous
with conflict economies.
ダイヤモンドは
紛争経済の代名詞でもあります
They're used to pay for weapons
and drugs.
武器や薬物の代金として
支払われる
So, they used this as seed money
for smuggling?
（天馬）
これを密輸の種銭にしてたのか
The Sister was buying weapons
and supporting foreign guerrillas?
シスターが武器を買って―
海外のゲリラを支援？
It doesn't fit.
ぴんとこない話だぜ
Anyway, these are the assets she seized
at Dejima.
とにかく 彼女が出島で
没収していた財産が これです
The rental cars were a shipping network,
as well as safes on wheels.
リースカーは
輸送ネットワークであり―
移動金庫そのものですよ
They could even load suicide bombers
on them.
しかも これに
自爆犯を乗せることもできる
If they did what Enomiya did with her men,
（雛河）以前 榎宮(えのみや)が―
襲撃犯を運ばせた手口と
同じようにすれば―
they could bypass street scanners.
街頭スキャナーも突破できる
Yes. But the important question is
where the remaining bombers are now.
（灼）はい でも重要なのは
残りの自爆犯の所在です
Let's find out.
ここで突き止めましょう
（通信機の着信音）
Analysis complete.
（志恩）解析完了
That system identifies cargo
using the rental cars' load sensors.
そこのシステムは―
リースカーの荷重センサーを介して
荷物を特定―
It controls all shipping.
輸送を一括管理してるわ
I've found signs that someone
checked this data recently.
（雛河）ここ数日―
何者かが データを参照した痕跡を
発見しました
Can you identify the user?
使用者の特定はできますか？
Let me see...
（志恩）えっと…
The user account belonged to
one of the administrators, Kurisu O'Brien.
使用された
ユーザーアカウントは―
管理者の１人で
久利須･オブライエン
If it was Kurisu, he'd have to be a ghost.
久利須では
幽霊になってしまいますね
The user was the Sister.
（灼）使用者はシスター うん…
What's wrong?
どうしたんですか？
I remembered something troubling
on the second floor.
２階に引っかかるものがあるのを
思い出したんです
This is a caregiver drone on
a life-support program, right?
（雛河）延命プログラムで動く
介護ドローンですね
This is the one thing
that doesn't make any sense.
（灼）これだけ
事件のどこにも当てはまらない
（携帯電話の着信音）
（一同）んっ
（雛河）あっ
（入江）ん…
（３人）あっ
Sister Shinogi, right?
（灼）シスター陵駕ですね？
Good job. You saw right through me.
（陵駕）お見通しね さすが
Who were you protecting here?
ここで 誰を守っていたんですか？
That doesn't matter now.
（陵駕）
今は それどころじゃないの
That's the suicide bombers' next target.
自爆テロの次の標的は そこよ
Get out, now!
（灼）えっ
早く逃げなさい
（シスターの悲鳴）
（一同）あっ
Where are you, Shinogi?!
（自爆犯）どこだ 陵駕！
出てこい！
Get out here!
（シスター）た… 助けて
Help!
Bring out Shinogi!
（自爆犯）陵駕を出せ！
Hey, calm down.
（入江）おいおい 落ち着け
Don't come any closer!
（自爆犯）
そ… それ以上 近づくな！
うっ わっ ううっ
The target's threat assessment
has been updated.
（ドミネーター）
対象の脅威判定が更新されました
Enforcement mode is Destroy Decomposer.
執行モード
デストロイ･デコンポーザー
Target will be completely eliminated.
対象を完全排除します
ご注意ください
Don't do it!
やめてください！
Prepare for drone disarmament!
ドローンで解除の準備を！
What are you thinking?!
（天馬）何やってんだ 監視官！
（灼）絶対 死なせない！
I won't let him die!
You'll never make it in time!
間に合うわけないだろ！
Give it a rest!
いいかげんにしろ！
What are you doing?!
何をするんだ！
Shut up!
（入江）うるせえ！　頼む！
（天馬）うん
Do it!
Got it!
了解！
（灼）ううっ
We could've saved him.
（灼）助けるべきだったのに
Inspector.
監視官…
He was a mad bomber coming after us!
俺たちを狙った爆弾野郎でもか！
No, you're wrong!
違う 違うんです！
The Sister said this place was the target!
シスターは この施設が標的だと
はっ
I get it. Both Joseph Auma
そう アウマ上人も
シスター陵駕も―
and Sister Shinogi
knew about the terrorist plan.
テロの計画を知っていた
They tried to stop it.
止めようとしたんだ
（２人）んっ…
Shion, can you trace the call
from Sister Shinogi?
志恩さん シスター陵駕からの通信
逆探知は？
Got it. The special zone
press event venue.
（志恩）見つけた
特区ＰＲイベント会場
The first bombing site.
最初の現場
（パトカーのサイレン）
（天馬･雛河･入江）あっ
He's conscious,
but seems to be in a vegetative state.
（雛河）意識は ありますが
植物状態のようです
The bed in the church
must've been for him.
恐らく 教会のベッドは
彼のためのものですね
So, the Sister was hiding out here.
（入江）ここに シスターは
隠れてやがったんだな
It looks that way.
We completely overlooked it.
（灼）そのようですね 盲点でした
Did she notice the trace and run?
逆探知に気づいて
逃げ出したのか？
No. She deliberately let us know
where she was.
違います わざと
居場所を知らせたんです
All so that we would take custody of him.
彼を俺たちに保護させるために
Can't we search Heaven's Leap yet?
（灼）教団の強制捜査は
まだですか！
Our undercover officers are taking
too long to make contact!
いくら何でも
潜入した２人からの連絡が遅すぎる
I'm working on it
with the Bureau of Culture!
（霜月）文化局と 絶賛 調整中
We sent them in there to find grounds
for a search in the first place.
そもそも 強制捜査の証拠集めに
潜入したんでしょうが
くっ
If we raid the place now, information
will leak and we'll come up empty-handed.
この状況でガサ入れしても―
どうせ情報漏れで空振りよ
We've been blocked
by believers in the Ministry of Welfare?
厚生省内の信者が
邪魔をしているんですね
If they haven't made contact
in another 12 hours,
（霜月）今後 12時間経過しても
連絡がない場合―
I'll make Bureau Chief Hosorogi
take action.
私が必ず細呂木(ほそろぎ)局長を動かす
You focus on clearing our way.
あなたは外堀を埋めることに
専念しなさい
Yes, ma'am.
（灼）はい
（霜月）ねえ
Listen, I know you're impatient,
but you can't push yourself too hard.
焦る気持ちは分かるけど
無理は禁物よ
（灼）ん？
I heard the report.
Your enforcers just saved your life.
報告は聞いてる
執行官に
命を助けられたばかりでしょ
Be grateful to them.
部下に感謝しなさい
I'm not impatient.
焦ってるんじゃなくて―
I want to prevent more victims,
whatever it takes.
どんな手を使ってでも
被害者を増やしたくないんです
You really are like Akane.
（霜月）あなた やっぱり
先輩に似てるわ
えっ？
I'm saying don't overdo it.
やりすぎるなってね
（通信機の着信音）
（霜月）おっ
Hello?
はい
This is Hanashiro at the MOFA.
（花城）外務省の花城よ
ああん？
We'll be taking Zaharias off your hands.
ザハリアスだけど
うちで引き取るわよ
What?!
（霜月）はあああ？
Trying to probe into
inspectors' affairs was foolish.
（トーリ）我々インスペクターを
探ろうとするとは愚かな
Just to be safe, let me
hear everything you know.
一応 知っていることは
すべて話してもらいましょう
"Inspectors"?
（炯）インスペクター？
うっ ぐっ…
Answer me.
（トーリ）答えろ でないと―
I trust you know what will happen
to her if you don't.
彼女がどうなるか
分かりますよね？
（炯）ああっ
You bastard!
貴様！
（炯のうめき声）
（荒い息）
Mom.
（トーリ）母さん
Have you gotten him to talk
about the MOFA, Torri?
トーリ 外務省のことは吐かせた？
Not yet, but I've taken measures.
まだだけど 手は打ってありますよ
To think Nisei had ties
to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
まさか 仁世が
外務省とつながっていたとはね
But now, we can eliminate their
influence from the immigrant community.
でも これで―
入国者コミュニティーから
やつらの影響を排除できる
Well done, Torri.
よくやったわね トーリ
Thank you very much.
（トーリ）ありがとうございます
How about your game, Mom?
母さんのゲームは どう？
It's going well.
There will be an opening in Bifrost soon.
（裁園寺）順調よ
ビフロストの椅子が空く日は近い
Bifrost?
（炯）ビフロスト…
Let's settle things
while we can still use Azusawa as a pawn.
（裁園寺）梓澤が手駒として
使えるうちに決着をつけましょう
The First is buttering you up, Mom.
ファーストは母さんに こびてるよ
He's a useful man, but a dangerous one.
やつは便利だけど 危険な男よ
I can only trust in the bond
between parent and child.
信用できるのは親子の絆だけ
That's right.
そうだね
Still, Kei Mikhail Ignatov.
（裁園寺）それにしても
炯･ミハイル･イグナトフ…
He's that Ignatov's brother, isn't he?
あのイグナトフの弟なのね
（炯）ああ…
ホホホホッ 油断しすぎかしら
Perhaps we were careless.
The fact you picked this place
（灼）
ここを指定したってことは―
means you had Heaven's Leap marked
long before we did.
俺たちより先に ヘブンズリープを
マークしてたんですね
Any basis for thinking so?
（花城）そう思う根拠は？
Zaharias is in their facility.
（灼）ザハリアスは
教団施設内にいる
We want the real one.
うちは本物を引っ張りたいの
If you know about that...
それが分かってるんなら…
Inspector Shindo, fall back!
慎導(しんどう)監視官
（霜月）ちょっと下がってて
（灼）でも
But...
Just follow my orders!
いいから！　従いなさい
（灼）くっ… はい
Yes, ma'am.
I'll get straight to the point.
When did the SAD infiltrate Heaven's Leap?
単刀直入に聞くけど―
行動課は
いつから教団に潜入してるの？
Stay out of domestic affairs.
国内の事案に首を突っ込まないで！
It's the other way around.
You're intruding on our territory.
逆よ
むしろ あなたたちが
こちらの領分に足を踏み入れている
What?
はあ？
As a kind of trade off,
（花城）
代わりにってわけじゃないけど―
I'll give you more information
about Sasagawa.
些々河(ささがわ)の件について
追加情報を教えておく
He was definitely killed by a fox.
彼を殺したのは―
狐で間違いない
Koichi Azusawa.
梓澤廣一(こういち)
He beat us to it!
はっ やられた
Watch the perimeter!
Detain all suspicious persons!
周辺を警戒
不審な人間を片っ端から拘束
Let's go back, Chief.
Kei and Mao are in danger.
課長 戻りましょう
炯たちが危ない
The SAD will handle things here.
（花城）この場は行動課が預かるわ
Ms. Hanashiro!
（霜月）花城さん
This makes us even.
これで借りはすべてチャラだから
Mr. and Mrs. Zaharias, who we held for
our investigation, have been murdered.
（霜月）潜入捜査のために
保護していた―
ザハリアス夫妻が殺害された
Possibly an internal split
in the group we're after,
捜査対象組織の内部分裂かと
思われるが―
but the details are hazy.
詳細は不明
Isn't that bad news?
（天馬）それって
やばいんじゃねえのか？
I know. I'll get a compulsory search
authorized somehow.
分かってる！
強制捜査の件は私が何とかする
Concentrate on your own responsibilities.
あなたたちは
自分たちの担当範囲に集中しなさい
（灼）ん…
I won't lose two subordinates
without a fight.
（霜月）
むざむざ 部下を２人も
失うわけにはいかない
I'll talk to the chief directly.
局長と直接 話してくる
Inspector Shindo,
慎導監視官
handle the scene.
（霜月）現場を頼みます
（灼）はい
Yes, ma'am.
（息を吸う音）
Shion, let's go over what we know.
志恩さん 情報を整理します
You got it.
了解
According to the SAD's info,
the same type of explosive was used.
（志恩）行動課からの情報で―
使用された爆弾は
これまでと同じタイプだった
That makes it the fifth
and last suicide bombing.
（灼）つまり ５発目
最後の自爆テロ
Nearby security footage
shows a rental car.
付近の防犯映像に
リースカーが記録されています
The same M.O., then.
（天馬）前の手口と一緒だな
Have you identified the young man
we found at the venue?
（灼）イベント会場で発見された
青年の身元は分かりましたか？
The child we took into custody
is Harris Sho Flannagan.
（志恩）保護した子供は
羽利須(はりす)＝生(しょう)･フラナガン
His father is Kurisu Kyoji O'Brien.
父親は
久利須＝矜治(きょうじ)･オブライエンよ
So he's Kurisu's kid?
（天馬）あのガキ 久利須の息子か
Why's he in a vegetative state?
（入江）何で植物状態に？
Due to an overdose
of Hue-improvement drugs.
（志恩）色相改善薬物の
過剰投与が原因
We detected abnormal quantities.
異常な量が検出された
Why did Sister Shinogi shelter him?
なぜ シスター陵駕が子供を？
Because he's her old colleague's kid.
昔の同僚の子供だからだろ
The Sister being a target demolishes
all our previous assumptions.
（灼）シスターが
標的になったことで―
過去の前提がすべて崩れた
The serial bombings have exposed
drug use in coefficient relief facilities,
連続爆破により―
係数緩和施設での
違法な薬物使用―
immigrants forced into prostitution,
and arms smuggling.
入国者の強制売春―
武器密造といった犯罪が暴露された
Meaning the culprit's goal
つまり 犯人の目的は―
is to indict this country
for the crimes it's forced on immigrants.
この国が
入国者たちに強いてきた―
犯罪の告発です
（一同）ええ？
Who's the culprit, then?
なら 誰が犯人だ？
Maybe a ghost.
幽霊かも
（２人）なっ
This is only speculation,
but Sister Shinogi warned us,
推測の域を出ないけど―
警告してきた シスター陵駕
Joseph Auma ambushed a bomber,
自爆犯を待ち伏せしたアウマ上人
Nisei's shut up in his facility,
施設に閉じ籠もる仁世
and Kurisu was murdered.
爆死した久利須
I think those four drew up a plan,
and someone else used it.
恐らく ４人で立てた計画が
誰かに利用された
Review the evidence we've found so far
with that in mind.
以上のことを踏まえて―
皆さんは 今までの証拠を
洗い直してください
And you, Inspector?
監視官は？
I've got an errand to run.
（灼）ちょっと やぼ用で
Inspector.
（入江）監視官
You're going to do
that "Mental Trace" thing, right?
メンタルトレースってやつを
やるつもりなんだな？
No.
（灼）違いますよ
You can't fool me
by calling it an "errand."
やぼ用なんて言い方じゃ
ごまかせないぜ
I'm here to stop you, for the enforcers.
執行官を代表して止めに来た
Please let me go.
行かせてください
Inspector Ignatov sent an email
to all us enforcers.
（入江）イグナトフ監視官が―
執行官全員に
メールを送ってたんだ
"Don't let Inspector Shindo
act recklessly."
“慎導監視官に
むちゃをさせるな”ってね
はっ ハァ…
ハッ あんたが倒れたら困るんだよ
We can't have you fainting again.
We might never see them again.
２人とも
二度と会えないかもしれない
なっ
Promises to the dead
are pretty demanding, huh?
死人との約束なんて
きついですよね
I'm heading out.
いってきます
I'll be fine, Kei.
俺は大丈夫だよ 炯
It's raining.
（灼）雨が降っている
（うめき声）
（灼）ああっ くっ
ハァ ハァ… ぐっ
ぐうっ ううっ…
（久利須の叫び声）
（灼のうめき声）
Damn it...
I knew it.
やっぱり―
He's alive.
生きてた
Kurisu O'Brien's alive.
久利須･オブライエン
（久利須のせき込み）
（久利須）うっ うう…
Going home?
（灼）帰国？　炯も舞(まい)ちゃんも？
Both of you?
Yes. The army called my brother
（炯）ああ 戦争で―
to active duty because of the war.
兄さんが軍隊に戻されるから
And I'm worried about my mother.
（舞子）私も
母さんが心配だから帰る
Dad says you'll both
be conscripted if you go.
行ったら ２人とも徴兵されるって
父さんが言ってた
And you're still going?
それでも 行くの？
That's normal, Arata.
Outside this country, anyway.
（炯）それが普通なんだ 灼
この国以外は
Don't worry. I'm sure
peace will come to our country, too.
大丈夫 きっと
私たちの国も平和になるから
Then we can come back to Japan.
そしたら また日本に戻れる
We'll come back.
必ず戻る
Yeah. I'll be waiting.
うん 待ってるよ
おっ
あっ
It's a promise.
約束だ
Yes, a promise.
ああ 約束だ
We'll all meet again.
（舞子）また ３人で
（ベッドの移動音）
（舞子）あっ
Maiko Maya Stronskaya, we have detected
an irregularity in your Hue.
（スタッフ）
舞子･マイヤ･ストロンスカヤさん
色相に異常が見られました
We'll rush you to a relief facility.
係数緩和施設に緊急移送します
But there was no problem
in my post-surgery checkup.
（舞子）あの
手術後の検査では問題ないと
Please, don't be alarmed.
（スタッフ）
大丈夫 ご安心ください
May Sibyl's blessings be upon you.
（信者たち）
シビュラの祝福が あらんことを
♪～
Stupid perfection in your own castle
How smart. You cause me to yawn
Look,
The key to the door is in your hand
Don't you let anyone take control
What do you want?
Go get it. Play by your own rule
The winner always controls the game
You stand in your belief
There's no promising future
Always helpless
Crying for the moon
Finger trembles in fear
With the weight of the trigger
There's a way for us
Show them how we fight
Pull the trigger
～♪
"Psycho-Pass" refers to the measurement
of a person's mind and personality.
This is a work of fiction. Any resemblance
to real persons or groups is coincidental.